Gitika Saksena

Vice President - Talent Management, Employee Experience and Talent Analytics at Accenture Technology in India

Summary

I am an HR Leader with more than twelve years of work experience. I have played diverse roles, including those in HR Business Partnering, HR Service Delivery, HR Transformation, Performance Management, Career Management, Talent Analytics, Employee Engagement & Recognition as well as Global Leadership Integration.

I have competence in managing HR processes at scale and through phases of growth and stability. My strength lies in anchoring initiatives from ideation to implementation, ability to assimilate different inputs as well as balancing multiple priorities for optimal outcomes.

I have extensive experience working with team members in other geographies including US, Europe, APAC and Latin America.

Core Skills include: Stakeholder management, Leadership partnering, Project and program management, HR Transformation and change management

My Gallup Top 5 Strengths: Futuristic, Ideation, Strategic, Achiever, Focus

Experience

Vice President - Talent Management, Employee Experience and Talent Analytics at AccentureSeptember 2015 - Present (1 year 7 months)

My key responsibilities include -

Anchoring the shift from traditional performance appraisal process to a strengths based performance framework.

Enabling insights driven decision by creating a defined agenda for the Talent Analytics stream.

Designing and implementing Employee Experience for Technology in India

Managing the career experience of Managing Directors and Associate Directors in India Technology

Global Leadership Integration Manager at Accenture

March 2015 - September 2015 (7 months)

I was responsible for designing, enabling and implementing the integration experience of our Leadership hires to Accenture across all its geographies and entities.

HR Business Partner for an industry vertical within Technology in India at Accenture

September 2012 - March 2015 (2 years 7 months)

Led HR for an industry vertical (with a headcount of 5000 plus) within Technology platform in India.

Partnered with Accenture Leadership aligned to the industry group to design the people agenda as well as implement key processes in the employee lifecycle, including performance rating calibrations, compensation reviews, identification of high potential and succession planning, grievance management etc. As a member of the HR Leadership Team for Technology in India, provided point of view and feedback on initiatives being driven cross entity and ensured the HR team in span of control implements programs effectively and consistently.

Led a team of 9 HR professionals.

Performance & Career Management, Employee Engagement and Recognition Specialist at Accenture September 2008 - August 2012 (4 years)

Designed and executed all Performance Management and Career Management Processes within Technology in India - Objective Setting, Mid-Year and Annual Performance Reviews, Relative Assessment, Career Development Planning and Performance Improvement Planning. Supported design and roll out of career paths/ tracks for the workforce involving review and evaluation of impact on key elements of the employee life cycle – talent acquisition, management, development and engagement. Managed Career Counselling framework for the entity, implement interventions for continued awareness and effectiveness of the programme.

HR Generalist at Accenture

April 2006 - August 2008 (2 years 5 months)

Leading HR for two key accounts within a business vertical. Business Partner for driving all people processes and designing specific people initiatives.

Senior Executive HR at Birlasoft

May 2004 - March 2006 (1 year 11 months)

Had separate roles including –

- i. Leading the Training and Development function for one of the India locations, responsible for end to end cycle including training needs assessment, determining nature of training delivery, reviewing training effectiveness etc.
- ii. Business HR partner for the business unit supporting the largest client for the organization

Skills & Expertise

Performance Management Employee Engagement Career Management Human Resources **Career Development**

Team Management

Personnel Management

Talent Management

Management

Recruiting

Leadership

Organizational Design

HR Consulting

Training

Management Consulting

Vendor Management

Deferred Compensation

Training Delivery

HR Service Delivery

Change Management

Communication

PCMM

Virtual Teams

Performance Appraisal

HR Policies

Employee Relations

Talent Acquisition

HR Transformation

Program Management

Education

Xavier Institute of Management, Bhubaneswar

MBA, Business Administration and Management, General, 2002 - 2004

Activities and Societies: Alumni Committee Lady Shri Ram College, University of Delhi

BA (Honours), Economics, 1999 - 2002

Activities and Societies: President, Quizzing Society

Interests

Photography

Languages

English

Hindi

(Full professional proficiency)

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Honors and Awards

HR Leadership Excellence Program

Accenture

Selected for Accenture Global HR Leadership Excellence Program, 2014 - 2015 - a niche leadership development programme for the select 30 high performing high potential HR professionals across all geographies.

Gitika Saksena

Vice President - Talent Management, Employee Experience and Talent Analytics at Accenture Technology in India



2 people have recommended Gitika

"Gitika is a very creative and passionate individual. The best think I liked about her is the high energy levels that she displayed even at the most difficult situations. Her strength lies in problem solving ability and out of the box thinking. A go-getter - results and task oriented individual with a good conceptual clarity."

— Martin Dinesh Gomez, managed Gitika at Accenture

"Gitika has a huge excitement kicking her up..when working HR initiatives & projects. She was part of key employee engagement, quality (PCMM), biz projects where her contribution & program management skills was valuable for the organisation."

— George Abraham SHRM - SCP, managed Gitika at Birlasoft

Contact Gitika on LinkedIn